Matthew Spaulding

Full Stack Developer

2584 Brandywine Dr. Clearwater, FL 33761 (727) 324-8369 mail@mattspaulding.org

SOCIAL PROFILES

MattSpaulding.org

Stack Overflow

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with over ten years of experience. Proven success in building software applications from conception to completion. Mentors and peer reviews junior developers. Active member of the development community, contributing to open source on GitHub with a Stack Overflow reputation of over 25K. Volunteers regularly as a sensei at the Coder Dojo, teaching kids how to code.

Github

LeetCode

EXPERIENCE

PwC, Tampa FL (Remote) — *Software Developer Manager*

MAR 2020 - PRESENT

- Developed an enterprise cloud-based web application for a global accounting firm.
- Worked with scrum masters and business analysts in an agile environment to manage development resources.
- Upholded a high standard code and design principles by participating in code reviewing pull requests.
- Developed on the MEAN stack (Mongo, Express, Angular, Node);
 implementing all aspects of the stack.
- Implemented microservices architecture with a monorepo using Nx.
- Utilized Azure DevOps ecosystem, creating work items, reviewing pull requests, and deployment pipelines.

LoanLogics, Jacksonville FL (Remote) — Lead Software Developer

OCT 2018 - DEC 2019

- Developed v1.0 of enterprise cloud-based web application for leading mortgage loan underwriting company.
- Worked with stakeholders to determine scope of project and staffing needs to complete the project by the deadline.
- Hired and mentored a team of 15 developers.
- Developed Angular v8 applications using the latest design patterns, such as NgRx, and connected to a Java Web API.
- Implemented microservices architecture for better scaling of independent development teams and fault isolation in production.
- Deployed in AWS DevOps ecosystem using Jenkins to deliver docker containers to a cluster of Amazon EC2 instances.
- Tested code with Jasmine, Karma, and Cypress.

SKILLS

Angular

Typescript

Javascript

NgRx/RxJS

HTML

SCSS

Node

Mongo

Express

C#

Web API

.Net Core

Entity Framework

Material Design

Bootstrap

Electron

NATIONALITY

US Citizen

iProcedures, Tampa FL (Remote) — Lead Software Developer

MAR 2016 - OCT 2018

- Developed a cloud-based mobile Anesthesia Information Management System (AIMS).
- Developed a real-time vitals monitor using the D3.js charting library.
- Created Windows and Mac desktop applications using Electron.
- Automated versioning and deployment system to deliver updates to clients using Azure DevOps Services.
- Peer reviewed junior developers using the Gitflow workflow.

Toptal, San Francisco CA (Remote) — *Software Developer*

SEPT 2015 - MAR 2016

The Learning Experience

- Created Bubble's U, a children's learning platform, for a nation-wide academy of early education.
- Developed in Angular v6 with custom UI components.
- Challenged with creating a unique, fun, child-usable web experience.
- link

Herndonwood Associates

- Created ReKoN, a risk management platform, for a banking institution.
- Developer in C#.Net using MVC pattern and JQuery Bootstrap frontend.
- Implemented Azure as the cloud server and storage solution.
- Created a multi-level role system.

Wolters Kluwer Law & Business, Tampa FL (Remote) — Software Developer

JAN 2014 - SEPT 2015

- Developed MediRegs, a medical coding suite, for a global provider of technology solutions.
- Built a tool that uses fuzzy logic to find ICD10 codes.
- Built with C#.Net and Angular.js in the Azure cloud.

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — Software Developer

NOV 2012 - OCT 2013

- Built the Office Depot Windows Store app.
- Worked with the Office Depot development team to create a custom API.

Agile Thought, Tampa FL — *Software Developer*

AUG 2012 - NOV 2012

• Built custom software using C#.Net with knockout.js frontend.

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — Software Developer

DEC 2011 - AUG 2012

- Converted several eCommerce websites into mCommerce mobile websites.
- Scraped HTML from the websites and presented the data as JSON through a RESTful C#.Net Web API.

Enporion, Tampa FL — Junior Software Developer

IAN 2011 - DEC 2011

- Developed an online reverse auction website for municipality utilities.
- Built with C#.Net MVC and Adobe Flex.

Raytheon, Largo FL — Junior Software Developer

MAY 2009 - JULY 2010

- Developed software for a major U.S. Defense company.
- Developed a tool to automate calibration of electrical equipment in Basic. (Voltameter, oscilloscope, etc.)

EDUCATION

University of South Florida, Tampa FL *Master of Science in Computer Engineering*

2011

GPA: 3.25

Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society President

PUBLICATIONS

Let's Build a Hacker News Clone with Dotnet Core and Angular

2020

YCombinator's infamous Hacker News has been a reliable source of news for the hacker community and, over time, has garnered the attention of hipsters and hustlers. Today we are building an app that displays the best stories from Hacker News.

link

Build Ultra-Modern Web Apps with Angular Material

2016

Material Design uses a paper metaphor, bold intentions, and meaningful motion to give user interfaces an ultra-modern feel. Web applications built using AngularJS can now easily adopt these design principles using Angular Material, a reference implementation of Google's Material Design Specification.

link

PERSONAL PROJECTS

GIVVN

- Developed a tool for nonprofit organizations to build communities and collect donations.
- SaaS platform allows nonprofits to build landing pages, automated chat bots, and donation forms.
- Built on the MEAN stack (Mongo, Express, Angular, Node) and deployed to Heroku.
- Uses Wit.ai for Natural Language Processing (NLP) to automate interactions.
- link